islamicity.com 2019-11-15

# Privacy Policy - IslamiCity

Skip to content 

* * *

At IslamiCity, we are committed to protecting your privacy. We use the information we collect about you to process your request of our product and services and also to provide a more personalized  experience during your visit to our site.

**What information do we collect? How do we use it?**  
When you place your request of our product and services, we may need to know your information that might include but not limited to your name, e-mail, address and credit card. This allows us to process and fulfill your your request, and to notify you about the status.

We may also use the information we collect to **** occasionally **** notify you about important functionality changes to the Web site, new services, and special offers we think you'll find valuable.

**How does IslamiCity protect customer information?**  
When you request of our product and services, we offer the use of a secure server. The secure server software (SSL) encrypts all information you input before it is sent to us. Furthermore, all of the customer data we collect is protected against unauthorized access.

**What about "cookies"?**  
"Cookies" are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. Our cookies do not contain any personally identifying information, but they do enable us to store your preference in so you don't need to redo it on your next visit. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser to prevent that.

**Will IslamiCity disclose the information it collects to outside parties?**  
IslamiCity does not sell, trade, or rent your personal information to others. Also, IslamiCity may provide aggregate statistics about our customers, sales, traffic patterns, and related site information to reputable third-party vendors, but these statistics will include no personally identifying information.

**Your consent**  
By using our Web site, you consent to the collection and use of this information by IslamiCity. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.

**Tell us what you think**  
IslamiCity welcomes your questions and comments about privacy. Please send e-mail to  or call us at 310-642-0006.

* * *

__

  1. ## Welcome to the New IslamiCity

We prepared this quick tour to help you get familiar with the new design so you find your way around the new site much quicker. 

Let's begin. 

  2. ## Topics Menu - Always one click away

Topics menu will always be here, always within reach. 

Here, you will find quick shortcuts to major topics & hubs under IslamiCity. 

  3. ## Site Search & Most Popular

Site search is also one click away. 

Here, you will also find the links to the most visited sections of IslamiCity, such as _Prayer times_ , _Hijri Converter_ , _Phonetic Search_ , _Quran Section_ , _IslamiCity Bazar_ and more. 

  4. ## Login & Login Status

If you need a Login or Registeration, this is your starting point. 

If you see a green icon like this ( __), it means you're already logged in!

But if you see, a red iconlike this ( __), it means you are NOT logged in.

It's all color coded. We'd love it if your icon is always green. It makes us a community. 

  5. ## Main Hubs & Home Pages

Everything under IslamiCity is categorized under the major hubs you see in this panel. Due to overwhelming content, each of these hubs can be considered a home page of its own. 

_Faith_ is where the tenets, pillars and spiruality related content is found. 

_Science_ section features not just Science but also Nature and Technology. This section is more for the technologically minded. 

_World_ section is for the News Buds. It covers day to day World Affairs, Politics & News. 

_Life_ section is all about Society, Art, Culture, History, Sports, Food, Music and much more. 

_Values_ section on the other hand is very special. We created it for only one thing in mind; to create a peaceful corner that features just inspiring and uplifting material, focused around _Universal Values_ to be reflect upon -- _at a time never needed more desperately than now_

  6. ## Inspiring Themes

Every other Friday, we try to feature a new theme which will uplift our spirituality. Our themes mostly focus on the universal values such as _compassion_ , _patience_ , _love_ and so on. 

We feature each theme with a beautiful image. _Click on these beautiful images & start exploring the theme/value behind it. _

* * *

TOPICS MENU
